[Music]
let's build an expanding triangular
array of squares where the first row has
1 1X one square the second row has 2 2x
two squares the third row has 3 3x3
squares the fourth row has four 4x4
squares and so on until the last row row
N has n and by n
squares the side length of this array is
the sum of the first n positive integers
which is n * n + 1 /
2 the line of slope -2 starting from the
top left hits the upper left corner of
the last Square in every row and
produces a triangle this triangle has
base length n * n +
1 the small triangles excluded from the
large triangle by the line can be
shifted and rotated to fill in miss gaps
at the large triangle like this
therefore the area of the original array
is 12 * n * n + 1 / 2 * n * n + 1 which
is the area of the triangle from this we
can see that the sum of the first n
positive cubes is equal to the square of
n * n + 1 / 2
[Music]